{"test_questions": [[{"question": "When transistors are used in digital circuits they usually operate in the:", "opta": "active region", "optb": "breakdown region", "optc": "saturation and cutoff regions", "optd": "linear region", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Three different Q points are shown on a dc load line. The upper Q point represents the:", "opta": "minimum current gain", "optb": "intermediate current gain", "optc": "maximum current gain", "optd": "cutoff point", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A transistor has a  of 250 and a base current, IB, of 20  A. The collector current, IC, equals:", "opta": "500  A", "optb": "5 mA", "optc": "50 mA", "optd": "5 A", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A current ratio of IC/IE is usually less than one and is called:", "opta": "beta", "optb": "theta", "optc": "alpha", "optd": "omega", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With the positive probe on an NPN base, an ohmmeter reading between the other transistor terminals should be:", "opta": "open", "optb": "infinite", "optc": "low resistance", "optd": "high resistance", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a C-E configuration, an emitter resistor is used for:", "opta": "stabilization", "optb": "ac signal bypass", "optc": "collector bias", "optd": "higher gain", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Voltage-divider bias provides:", "opta": "an unstable Q point", "optb": "a stable Q point", "optc": "a Q point that easily varies with changes in the transistor's current gain", "optd": "a Q point that is stable and easily varies with changes in the transistor\u0092s current gain", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To operate properly, a transistor's base-emitter junction must be forward biased with reverse bias applied to which junction?", "opta": "collector-emitter", "optb": "base-collector", "optc": "base-emitter", "optd": "collector-base", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ends of a load line drawn on a family of curves determine:", "opta": "saturation and cutoff", "optb": "the operating point", "optc": "the power curve", "optd": "the amplification factor", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If VCC = +18 V, voltage-divider resistor R1 is 4.7 k, and R2 is 1500, what is the base bias voltage?", "opta": "8.70 V", "optb": "4.35 V", "optc": "2.90 V", "optd": "0.7 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The C-B configuration is used to provide which type of gain?", "opta": "voltage", "optb": "current", "optc": "resistance", "optd": "power", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Q point on a load line may be used to determine:", "opta": "VC", "optb": "VCC", "optc": "VB", "optd": "IC", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A transistor may be used as a switching device or as a:", "opta": "fixed resistor", "optb": "tuning device", "optc": "rectifier", "optd": "variable resistor", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If an input signal ranges from 20\u201340 A (microamps), with an output signal ranging from .5\u20131.5 mA (milliamps), what is the ac beta?", "opta": "0.05", "optb": "20", "optc": "50", "optd": "500", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is beta's current ratio?", "opta": "IC/IB", "optb": "IC/IE", "optc": "IB/IE", "optd": "IE/IB", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A collector characteristic curve is a graph showing:", "opta": "emitter current (IE) versus collector-emitter voltage (VCE) with (VBB) base bias voltage held constant", "optb": "collector current (IC) versus collector-emitter voltage (VCE) with (VBB) base bias voltage held constant", "optc": "collector current (IC) versus collector-emitter voltage (VC) with (VBB) base bias voltage held constant", "optd": "collector current (IC) versus collector-emitter voltage (VCC) with (VBB) base bias voltage held constant", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With low-power transistor packages, the base terminal is usually the:", "opta": "tab end", "optb": "middle", "optc": "right end", "optd": "stud mount", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a silicon diode is forward biased, what is VBE for a C-E configuration?", "opta": "voltage-divider bias", "optb": "0.4 V", "optc": "0.7 V", "optd": "emitter voltage", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the current gain for a common-base configuration where IE = 4.2 mA and IC = 4.0 mA?", "opta": "16.80", "optb": "1.05", "optc": "0.20", "optd": "0.95", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a PNP circuit, the most positive voltage is probably:", "opta": "ground", "optb": "VC", "optc": "VBE", "optd": "VCC", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a 2 mV signal produces a 2 V output, what is the voltage gain?", "opta": "0.001", "optb": "0.004", "optc": "100", "optd": "1000", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The symbol hfe is the same as:", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "hi-fi", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most of the electrons in the base of an NPN transistor flow:", "opta": "out of the base lead", "optb": "into the collector", "optc": "into the emitter", "optd": "into the base supply", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a transistor, collector current is controlled by:", "opta": "collector voltage", "optb": "base current", "optc": "collector resistance", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Total emitter current is:", "opta": "IE \u2013 IC", "optb": "IC + IE", "optc": "IB + IC", "optd": "IB \u2013 IC", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Often a common-collector will be the last stage before the load; the main function(s) of this stage is to:", "opta": "provide voltage gain", "optb": "provide phase inversion", "optc": "provide a high-frequency path to improve the frequency response", "optd": "buffer the voltage amplifiers from the low-resistance load and provide impedance matching for maximum power transfer", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a C-C configuration to operate properly, the collector-base junction should be reverse biased, while forward bias should be applied to which junction?", "opta": "collector-emitter", "optb": "base-emitter", "optc": "collector-base", "optd": "cathode-anode", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The input/output relationship of the common-collector and common-base amplifiers is:", "opta": "270 degrees", "optb": "180 degrees", "optc": "90 degrees", "optd": "0 degrees", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a transistor operates at the middle of the dc load line, a decrease in the current gain will move the Q point:", "opta": "off the load line", "optb": "nowhere", "optc": "up", "optd": "down", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is the higher gain provided by a C-E configuration?", "opta": "voltage", "optb": "current", "optc": "resistance", "optd": "power", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the collector current for a C-E configuration with a beta of 100 and a base current of 30 A?", "opta": "30 A", "optb": ".3 A", "optc": "3 mA", "optd": "3 MA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}